# RAIN LEUNG

## Summary

Passionate and interest-driven data engineer focusing on Data, Software Engineering, and AI/ML. Self-taught generalist across several fields. Active participant of competitive programming contests on 3+ platforms (see <u>GitHub</u>), with 7+ years of programming experience since high school. A fast learner, team player, and the "chameleon" that adapts to fast-changing environments.

#### Work Experience

Data Engineer Sep 2024 – Present

Lalamove

Hong Kong

- Developed and maintained backend functionalities (databases, APIs, cloud servers, etc.) for several data-related web applications and micro-services.
- Monitored above projects with metrics and alerts, and responded to incidents to ensure >99.9% uptime.
- Configured, built, and released containerized applications based on CI tools and workflows.
- No further details available (signed NDA).

Summer Intern Jun 2023 – Aug 2023

MTR Corporation Limited

Hong Kong

- Built and maintained a new ETL data pipeline from scratch with Python for internal room booking reports, and optimized it with multi-processing to reduce >75% time overhead.
- Developed web crawlers for 700+ Glassdoor employee reviews and conducted sentiment analysis with NLTK, and presented data in dashboards.
- Migrated and automated old Octopus application process with SharePoint List and Power Automate, from manual inputs to a new semi-auto flow.
- Assisted with UAT, ran test cases, and issued tickets using Redmine.
- Created dashboards and reports for ESG statistics.

#### Education

### The University of Hong Kong

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science, Second Class Honours (Division One)

Sep 2021 – Jun 2024 cGPA 3.32 / 4.3

#### PolyU Hong Kong Community College

Associate in Engineering, Distinction

Sep 2019 - Jun 2021

cGPA 3.77 / 4.0

#### Relevant Coursework

- Data Science and Engineering
- Software Engineering
- Data Structures
- Computer Architecture
- Algorithm Design
- Computer Networking
- Artificial Intelligence
- Machine Learning

- Natural Language Processing
- Computer Vision

### Technical Skills

Languages Python, Java, C, C++, C#, Kotlin, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL, R, Octave

Data & AI/ML NumPy, Pandas, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Keras, MLflow, BeautifulSoup, Matplotlib, Selenium

Database MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB, HBase, Neo4j

Web Development Flask, FastAPI, Spring Boot, Jekyll

Miscellaneous Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, GitHub, GitLab, AWS, Azure, Tableau, Jira, Redmine,

Unity, Android Studio, Arduino, Verilog, AutoCAD, SolidWorks, QT, Figma

Aug 2021

Oct 2020

Oct 2020

Dean's List

Director's List

PolyU Hong Kong Community College

PolyU Hong Kong Community College

PolyU Hong Kong Community College

**Outstanding Student Award**